A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Joan R. Dassin FA660
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Joan R. Dassin
1959-1996, bulk 1984-1996
1984-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Dassin, Joan
Ford Foundation
FA660
4.8 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains program reviews and program history materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 4 series:
1. Field Offices and Regional Meeting.
2. Program Reviews.
3. Program History and Background.
4. Cuba.
Biographical / Historical
Joan Dassin is an educator, scholar, and former foundation executive who worked for a number of years at the Ford Foundation. Dassin originally worked in the Ford Foundation's program for Latin America before becoming Director of its International Fellowships Program.
Dassin's career at the Ford Foundation began in its program for Brazil where she worked as a Program Officer before becoming the Foundation's Representative for Brazil. In 1992, she was appointed Regional Director for Latin America and the Caribbean. She later worked as a Consultant to the Ford Foundation Office for the Andean Region and the Southern Cone. From 2000 to 2013, she directed the Foundation's International Fellowships Program.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Dassin became a professor of international education and development at the Heller School for Social Policy and Management. Dassin earned a B.A. in English and American literature from Brandeis University and a Ph.D. in modern thought and literature from Stanford University.
- Field Offices and Regional Meeting, 1989-1994; I
  - Latin America and the Caribbean Regional Meeting, 1994 April 17-23 (Box 1)
  - Latin American Regional Meeting -- Briefing Books, 1994 April 18-20 (Box 1)
  - Andean Region Southern Cone, 1990 April 4 (Box 1)
  - Brazil Field Office, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Future of Lima, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Lima Office Closing, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - Mexico Field Office, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - Santiago Field Office, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
- Program Reviews, 1982-1995; II
  - Developing Country Programs -- Latin Amerca and the Caribbean Program Review FY 1983, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Brazil Program Review FY 1985, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Latin America and the Caribbean Program Review FY 1987, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Andean Region and Southern Cone Program Review FY 1986, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Mexico and Central America Program Review FY 1987, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Latin America and the Caribbean Program Review FY 1988, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Andean Region and the Southern Cone Program Review FY 1989, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Mexico and Central America FY 1989, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Brazil FY 1989, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Research Agenda for US-Mexico Studies, 1989 February 14-16 (Box 2)
  - Caribbean-Latin America Biennial Budget FY 1990-1991, 1989 April (Box 2)
  - Mexico City -- FY 1990-1991 Biennial Budget Program Review, 1989 April (Box 2)
  - Rio de Janiero -- FY 1990-1991 Biennial Budget Program Review, 1989 April (Box 2)
  - Haiti Democratic Needs Assessment, 1989 May (Box 2)
  - Developing Country Programs -- Latin America and the Caribbean FY 1989, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Caribbean -- Latin American Regional -- FY 1990 Program Review, 1990 April (Box 2)
  - Overview of Program -- Brazil, 1990 September (Box 2)
  - Latin America Regional -- FY 1991 Program Review, 1991 April (Box 2)
  - International Directory of Foundations with Grant Programs in Latin America, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Overview of Program -- Mexico and Central America, 1992 March (Box 2)
  - A Summary of the Proceedings of the Ford Foundation Latin America and the Caribbean Program Review, 1992 May 6 (Box 2)
  - Program Review -- Caribbean, 1992 May (Box 2)
  - Latin America Regional -- Program Review, 1992 May (Box 2)
  - Mexico City -- Program Review, 1992 May (Box 2)
  - Rio de Janeiro -- Program Review, 1992 May (Box 2)
  - Santiago -- Program Review, 1992 May (Box 2)
  - Caribbean -- Program Reviews, 1993 March (Box 2)
  - Latin America Regional -- Program Reviews, 1993 March (Box 2)
  - Mexico City -- Program Reviews, 1993 March (Box 2)
  - Rio de Janeiro -- Program Reviews, 1993 March (Box 2)
  - Santiago -- Program Reviews, 1993 March (Box 2)
  - Biennial Program Review, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Program Review, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Board Text / Program Reviews, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Program Review March 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- Program History and Background, 1959-1996; III
  - Background Papers, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Cuba/Haiti Background, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Draft Brochure, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Environment and Development in Latin America, 1993 (Box 3)
  - History of the Latin American Program, 1961-1992 (Box 3)
  - Program History, 1967-1989 (Box 3)
  - History of the Latin American Program, 1959-1980 (Box 3)
  - History of the Latin American Program, 1972-1991 (Box 3)
  - History of the Latin America, 1970-1996 (Box 3)
  - Program Reports (1/2), 1994 (Box 3)
  - Program Reports (2/2), 1994 (Box 3)
  - Reproductive Health / Background, 1991-1995 (Box 3)
- Cuba, 1967-1994; IV
  - Cuba, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
  - Cuba DAP Proposals [PHOTOS], 1980-1983 (Box 4)
  - Cuba -- Jeff Puryear Information, 1967-1985 (Box 4)
  - Cuban-Americans Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Cuba -- Miscellaneous Information -- Staff Meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Cuba Background II, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
  - Cuba -- Ford Programs -- History, 1967-1989 (Box 4)